Finding Aid for the Herschel Burke Gilbert Papers PASC-M.0268
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Project Development, Series 4.
  - Last Temptation, The, 1957 January 25 (Box 280)
    story presentation by Alfred Perry
  - Last Temptation, The, 1957-1959 (Box 280)
    correspondence with Joseph Viertel (author of book)
  - Last Temptation, The, 1958 (Box 280)
    correspondence (inc Max Youngstein) of writers to be contacted and considered
  - Last Temptation, The, 1957-1959 (Box 280)
    correspondence; agreements; reviews; financial papers; options agreement; correspondence with: Intercontinental Films Limited; Ben Oyserman; regarding Delbert Mann; H. Gilbert vision statement; structure statement; motion picture outline; story continuity from book by Pearl Kenmonth; rights agreement; publication agreement; press releases
  - Male Animal, The, 1939-1941 (Box 256)
    synopsis and published play
    By James Thurber and Elliot Nugent.
  - Man Who Stole the Word Beautiful, The, 1967 (Box 256)
    script covers, song title sheets.
  - Man Who Stole the Word Beautiful, The (Box 257)
    revised "A" script bruning masters
  - Man Who Stole the Word Beautiful, The, 1967 (Box 257)
    script with lyrics, bruning masters
  - Man Who Stole the Word Beautiful, The, 1968 (Box 257)
    comments and reactions from Berkeley performance of the tape
  - Man Who Stole the Word Beautiful, The, 1967 (Box 257)
    publicity and public relations
  - Man Who Stole the Word Beautiful, The, 1967-1968 (Box 257)
    script, correspondence including letter to Danny Kaye
  - Notebook with lyrics of Alfred Perry (Box 265)
  - Opera Ideas, 1958, 1970 (Box 257)
    Opera ideas, programs, newspaper clippings
  - Project Temp., 1965 (Box 286)
    Book of Charts called "Project Temp" by Carroll Knudson, 1965 showing the relationship between tempo, timing and beats based on the speed of 35 M.M. film as standardized by the Academy of Motion Picture Arts & Sciences at 90 feet per minute.
  - The Hot and the Cool, screenplay 2nd Draft, 1957 October (Box 287)
    by Eliot Asinof, from a treatment by Alfred Perry, based on the novel by Edwin Gilbert, Office File, Second Draft
  - The Whistling Shadow, 1956 (Box 263)
    by John Harding, Mack David, Herschel Gilbert
  - Unidentified Project, 1964-1968,1971 (Box 257)
    miscellaneous newspaper clippings 1964-1968 and letter from "Dr. Seuss" (Theodor S. Geisel) 1971
  - Whistling Shadow, The (Box 240)
    John Harding contracts and notes; location suggestions in Gilbert's hand; partial script; rewrite notes; Mabel Seeley contract; treatment; story outline; assignment of rights; contracts; 2nd draft script; Max Youngstein (United Artists) correspondence.
  - Whistling Shadow, The (Box 249)
    plot suggestions, suggested story changes, by Richard Bernstein
  - Whistling Shadow, The, 1956 August 2 (Box 287)
    Screenplay, The Whistling Shadow, a murder-mystery with music from the novel of Mabel Seeley, screenplay by John Briard Harding, Lyrics by Mack David, music by Herschel Burke Gilbert, first draft.
- Corrrespondence, Series 5.
  General correspondence, or preliminarily processed correspondence is found here. See also correspondence under specific productions.
  - 2 Herschel Burke Gilbert letters, 1965 March 30 (Box 251)
    after retiring from CBS referring to enclosed record albums
  - ASCAP, 1957 (Box 268)
    Richard Murray regarding claims for credit for various music cues used in film and television, includes Writers Distribution Formula 1957
  - Assorted Correspondence, 1950-1969 (Box 253)
  - Between Gilbert and Martin Machat, law office (RKO-Lamas Music Corp), 1956-1958 (Box 252)
  - Correspondence (Box 253)
    most with Al Tamarin re: United Artists music, including Sabre Jet assignment to Marlen Music
  - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 269)
  - Correspondence from L.M. Fine (Who's Who in Music), Johnny Green (Metro Goldwyn Mayer Studios), 1956 (Box 271)
  - Correspondence re establishment of Laurel Records and John Paul Music, 1967 (Box 252)
  - Correspondence with Bob Silverman, Tamarin Music, then Mills Music (Box 253)
  - Easy, 1959 (Box 279)
    song, music by Camino Ravosa lyric by Hal Halverstadt and record-music reports
  - Edizioni Musicali Edward Kassner (Box 289)
    Italy, John Paul Music.
  - Edward Kassner Music Co, Ltd, John Paul Music (Box 289)
  - Edward Kassner Music Co. (Canada), Ltd. John Paul Music Corp (Box 288)
  - From Arthur H. Nadel to H. Gilbert, 1964 April (Box 269)
    Universal City Studios.
  - From Ed Sheftel regarding "The Unit", 1973 (Box 268)
    within a single cabinet combines 4 sound modulating instruments
  - from Fred Karlin to Herschel Gilbert (Box 288)
    regarding congratulations on Herschel's award from the Film Music Society
  - From Gilbert to Miss Vera Caspary regarding "The Whistling Shadow", 1957 (Box 268)
  - Herb Jeffries Recording (Box 271)
    Herb Jeffries recording, financial papers and correspondence related to Richard P. Hazard claim vs RKO Unique Records 1957 Trial Board of Local 47, AFofM
  - John Paul Music (Box 288)
    miscellaneous correspondence
  - John Paul Music Corp., 1960-1968 (Box 272)
  - Legal answer filed by Cadet Records, 1961 (Box 271)
    in the matter of Gilbert, et al vs. Cadet Records
  - Letter from Saul at Bourne Inc. Music Publishers to Gilbert (Box 251)
    re: A Man is as Good as His Word and Comanche music
  - Marlen Music Company, 1957-1958 (Box 268)
    includes agreements
  - MCA - Louis De Rochmont (Box 258)
  - Me and Benjy, 1967 (Box 268)
    song and score
  - Music Corporation of America, 1951-1958 (Box 269)
  - Musician's Union Memos (Box 251)
    Memos to and from Herschel B Gilbert re: Musicians Union on RKO Pictures letterhead
  - Notice of address change for John Paul Music (Box 253)
  - Performing Rights Society Copyright House, 1958 (Box 269)
    London.
  - Pertaining to Multiple Productions, 1959-1993 (Box 270)
  - Pertaining to Multiple Production Titles, 1938, 1955-1967 (Box 271)
  - Re: Album "Music from Television", 1959 (Box 279)
    from John Paul Music Corp to Capitol Records
  - Re: Candide (Box 271)
    Special Symphony Concert, Santa Monica, CA, May 31, 1969, program with handwritten note from Gilbert to Leonard Bernstein regarding conducting of the overture to "Candide"
  - Re: Don't Be Afraid, 1959 (Box 279)
    song, words and music by Calvin Bostic
  - Re: Everyman Sing, 1958 (Box 279)
    song music by Hylton Socher lyrics by Ronald Miller, attached sheet for contract between John Paul Music Corp and Miller/Socher
  - Re: Fidel Rock, 1959 (Box 279)
    music by Edward Ocnoff lyric by Lee Bishop and Edward Ocnoff
  - Re: Pretty Green Shawl, 1959 (Box 279)
    song, music by Hylton Socher lyrics by Ronald Miller, to Dot Records, Gallatin, TN.
  - Regarding use of music between Gilbert and Campbell Connelly and Co. Ltd, Music Publishers, London, 1958 (Box 268)
  - Reminiscences of composer Arthur Lange and business partner Ernst Klapholz (Box 290)
    Material recorded mid-1950s, binder of conversation
  - Royalties and Rights, 1962-1968 (Box 241)
    Correspondence re: Italian royalties.
  - Royalties and Rights, 1977-1978 (Box 250)
    Correspondence and index cards sent by Herschel Burke Gilbert to ASCAP.
  - Royalties and Rights (Box 255)
    Correspondence between Herschel Burke Gilbert and ASCAP regarding foreign royalties 1960s.
  - Songwriters' Protective Association letter to HB Gilbert re: Edward Ocnoff contract with John Paul Music (Box 251)
  - The Performing Rights Society, 1958 (Box 269)
    includes cue sheets and blank forms
  - Trade Wind Tours of Hawaii correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 272)
    related to series of seminars in the southeastern region of the US
  - United Airlines correspondence, 1972 May (Box 272)
    regarding "Hello Hawaii" inner liner for album and information regarding United airlines version of the album and United Airlines Mainliner Magazine May 1972
  - United Artists Corporation, correspondence and publicity, 1957 (Box 270)
    in "The Cash Box", v. 19, no. 13
  - Univ. of Wyoming (Box 271)
  - Unsigned agreements for various productions and correspondence, 1957-1961 (Box 268)
- Associations & Organizations, Series 6.
  Professional and personal
  Arranged alphabetically by association/organization name.
  - Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences, 1966 December (Box 247)
    , Music Branch Executive Committee - lists of songs eligible for Best Song Award, and Classification of pictures for Music scoring Awards December 1966 for the 39th Annual Academy Awards
  - Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences (Box 249)
    Music Rules Committee minutes of meetings
  - Academy of Motion Picture Arts & Sciences, 1955 (Box 249)
    booklet - Rules for the Conduct of the Balloting, 28th Awards
  - Academy of Motion Picture Arts & Sciences, 1952 (Box 249)
    25th Awards, Revised rules for music awards
  - Academy of Motion Picture Arts & Sciences (Box 249)
    List of Motion Picture Academy members lists of songs eligible and not eligible with reasons (1953?)
  - Academy of Motion Picture Arts & Sciences, 1956 (Box 249)
    Music Rules Committee minutes (29th Awards) 1st draft
  - Academy of Motion Picture Arts & Sciences, 1955-1956 (Box 249)
    Music Rules Committee members, list of problems
  - Academy of Motion Picture Arts & Sciences, 1955-1956 (Box 249)
  - Academy of Motion Picture Arts & Sciences, 1956 April 26 (Box 249)
    memo from Music Branch Executive Committee
  - Academy of Motion Picture Arts & Sciences (Box 249)
    screening schedules
  - Academy of Motion Picture Arts & Sciences (Box 249)
    music and songs nominations ballots
  - Academy of Motion Picture Arts & Sciences, 1956-1957 (Box 249)
    invitation & response card to 28th Awards, March 21, 1956 & 1957 invitation
  - Academy of Motion Picture Arts & Sciences, 1956 (Box 249)
    invitations to showings, mostly 1956 (for 1955)
  - Academy of Motion Picture Arts & Sciences, 1955 March 30 (Box 249)
    27th Awards program, March 30, 1955 (Carmen Jones)
  - Academy of Motion Picture Arts & Sciences (Box 249)
    invitations to showings, Price Waterhouse response envelopes
  - Academy of Motion Picture Arts & Sciences, 1956 January 1 (Box 249)
    booklet - Membership List as of Jan 1, 1956 with corrections & additions
  - Academy of Motion Picture Arts & Sciences (Box 249)
    28th Awards booklet - Rules for the Conduct of the Balloting
  - Academy of Motion Picture Arts & Sciences (Box 249)
    Proposal for Invitation to Membership card
  - Academy of Motion Picture Arts & Sciences, 1956 (Box 249)
    Telegram - to Herschel Burke Gilbert re: 1st meeting of the 29th Academy Awards music rules committee
  - Academy of Motion Picture Arts & Sciences, 1957 (Box 249)
    Telegram - to Herschel Burke Gilbert re: meeting of Academy Awards music branch executive committee
  - Academy of Motion Picture Arts & Sciences, 1956 (Box 249)
    Telegram - to Herschel Burke Gilbert re: Academy Awards music executive committee meeting
  - Academy of Motion Picture Arts & Sciences, 1956 (Box 249)
  - Academy of Motion Picture Arts & Sciences (Box 249)
    lists, rules, bulletins, minutes of music committees, screening invitations
  - Academy of Motion Picture Arts & Sciences, 1954 (Box 249)
    invitation to Awards, nominations (The Moon is Blue)
  - Academy of Motion Picture Arts & Sciences, 1952 (Box 249)
    screening calendars, Academy Award Winning Pictures
  - Academy of Motion Picture Arts & Sciences, 1952 February (Box 249)
    invitation to Awards complete, in original envelope
  - Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences, 1972 (Box 271)
    letter with copy of news release
  - Academy of Motion Picture Arts & Sciences, 2001 (Box 271)
    Pamphlet "An Academy Tribute to Elmer Bernstein"
  - Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences, 1954-1961 (Box 271)
    publication for the Rules for the conduct of the balloting 27th(1954), 31-32(1958-59), 33-34(1960-61) annual academy awards
  - Academy of Motion Pictures Arts and Sciences, 1957 (Box 278)
    Academy of Motion Pictures Arts & Sciences - 29th Annual 1957 material (for 1956 achievements) including lists of eligible releases, screenings notices, music branch memos & telegram notices of meetings, Academy Report bulletin to members, pamphlet re: the 1/4 of 1% plan to provide funds to pay for telecast/broadcast of Awards show
  - Academy of Motion Pictures Arts and Sciences, 1958-1970 (Box 278)
    Academy of Motion Pictures Arts & Sciences - 30th Annual 1958 material (for 1957 achievements) including lists of eligible releases, screenings notices, music branch memos & telegram notices of meetings, Academy Report bulletin to members, invitation to Academy Board of Governors dinner
  - Academy of Motion Pictures Arts and Sciences, 1958-1970 (Box 278)
  - Academy of Motion Pictures Arts and Sciences, 1959 (Box 278)
    Academy of Motion Pictures Arts & Sciences - 31st Annual 1959 material (for 1958 achievements) including lists of eligible releases, screenings notices, music branch memos & telegram notices of meetings, Academy Report bulletin to members, invitation to the Academy Awards presentation
  - Academy of Motion Pictures Arts and Sciences, 1960 (Box 278)
    Academy of Motion Pictures Arts & Sciences - 32nd Annual 1960 material (for 1959 achievements) including lists of eligible releases, screenings notices, music branch telegram notices of meetings, Academy Report bulletin to members, official nomination ballot for Best Picture of the Year Award with reply envelope
  - Academy of Motion Pictures Arts & Sciences, 1973 November 5 (Box 278)
    Folder for music subcommittee
  - Academy of Motion Pictures Arts & Sciences, 1974 October 28 (Box 278)
  - Academy of Motion Pictures Arts & Sciences (Box 278)
    Booklet: What is the Academy?, Academy Report to members
  - Academy of Motion Pictures Arts & Sciences (Box 278)
    Form letter from Johnny Green to Herschel Gilbert re: congratulations on nomination and rules/suggestions for telecast; 2 parking stickers with instructions
  - Academy of Motion Pictures Arts & Sciences, 1962 (Box 278)
    34th Annual 1962 material (for 1961 achievements) schedule of preliminary screenings
  - Academy of Motion Pictures Arts & Sciences, 1961 (Box 278)
    33rd Annual 1961 material (for 1960 achievements) including lists of eligible releases, screenings notices, official nomination ballot for music awards
  - AFofM, 1954 April (Box 288)
    "international musician" - AFofM Journal,
  - AFTRA (Box 272)
    American Federation of Television and Radio Artists (AFTRA) code of fair practice for phonograph records and blank forms
  - American Federation of Musicians, 1948, 1964-1990 (Box 242)
    : Phonograph Record Labor Agreement booklets 1964, 1969, 1972, 1973, 1975, 1977,1981, 1983-86, 1988, 1989, 1990; Basic Theatrical Motion Picture Agreement booklets: 1964-1969, 1969-1970, 1972-1974; Phonograph Record Trust Agreement booklets: 1964, 1969, 1972, 1973, 1976, 1977, 1979, 1982, 1984, 1987; AFofM Musicians' and Employers' Pension Welfare Fund booklet 1981; Article by President James C. Petrillo, 1948; Trust Funds signatories booklets; correspondence, contracts, lists; Phono recording scales effective 1974-1975 45th Report 7/1/1970- 6/30/1971 and 49th Report July 1, 1972 booklet, Music Performance Trust Funds; Music Performance Trust Funds reports and correspondence; price lists 1969; Anderson Case claim documents; Television and Radio Commercial Announcements Agreement booklet, 1966-1969
  - American Federation of Musicians (Box 247)
    Wage scales, hours of employment, working conditions applying to motion picture work
  - American Federation of Musicians, 1948 September 1 (Box 247)
  - American Federation of Musicians, 1951 (Box 271)
    television film agreement
  - American Federation of Musicians, 1958-1960 (Box 271)
    by-laws,information and notices
  - American Federation of Musicians and Musicians Mutual Protection Associations, 1949-1957 (Box 272)
    agreements, brochures, correspondence and blank agreement forms and logs 1949-57, pamphlets "Who Profits from Recorded Music?" and "The Story of An Innocent Little Record That became a Monster"
  - American Guild of Authors and Composers, 1954-1961 (Box 242)
    Articles of Agreement, Constitution and By-Laws (1954), Collection of Royalty Plan, (9/16/1959), 1959 correspondence and lists, Bulletin and List of Members, 1961
  - American Society of Composers, Authors, and Publishers (Box 248)
    Statement
  - American Society of Music Arrangers (ASMAC) (Box 273)
    later the American Society of Music Arrangers and Composers (ASMAC) including minutes of meetings, copies of The Score publication, correspondence, notes on issues
  - ASCAP, 1969 (Box 246)
    Form letters to SCA and ASCAP members, ASCAP member protest
  - ASCAP, 1952 August-1958 October (Box 261)
    General membership meetings
  - ASCAP, 1954 (Box 261)
    Annual membership meeting
  - ASCAP, 1956 (Box 261)
    New President, Paul Cunningham
  - ASCAP, 1958-1978 (Box 261)
    Licensed Radio Stations
  - ASCAP, 1958-1978 (Box 261)
    Licensed Television Stations
  - ASCAP, 1952-1958 (Box 261)
    Member Brochures: 1952,53,58
  - ASCAP, 1959 (Box 261)
    program guide 1959 Jazz listings
  - ASCAP, 1959 (Box 261)
    program guide 1959 Travel and Vacation Category listings
  - ASCAP, 1958 (Box 261)
    program guide 1958 > 1,000,000 Copies Sold Category listings
  - ASCAP, 1959 (Box 261)
    program guide 1959 Fashion & Beauty Category listings
  - ASCAP, 1957 (Box 261)
    program guide 1957 Music From Motion Pictures Category listings
  - ASCAP, 1958 (Box 261)
    program guide 1958 Gifts and Toys Category listings
  - ASCAP (Box 288)
    correspondence re: John Paul Music
  - ASCAP BMI, 1972 January 4 (Box 253)
    Variety article - High & Low Notes by Elizabeth Murphy: ASCAP & BMI Clash Over Royalties
  - ASMA, 1988; VHS (Box 266)
    50th Anniv. John Williams Golden Score Award Retrospective
  - ASMA (Box 288)
    postcards notices of board meetings addressed to members
  - ASMA (Box 288)
    postcards, 2 notices of meetings, 2 solicitations of information for Scoreboard section of The Score
  - ASMA, 1944 January (Box 288)
    The Score, January 1944 (Vol. 2 No. 1)
  - ASMA, 1989 July 15; audio cassette (Box 296)
  - ASMA, 1994 February 16; audio cassette (Box 296)
    lunch - Marc Shaiman
  - ASMA, 1990 October 27; audio cassette (Box 296)
    luncheon Artie Shaw, Gilbert speaks re: Joe Mullendore & David Rose.
  - ASMA, audio cassette (Box 296)
    Frank De Vol luncheon.
  - ASMA, 1989 September 23; audio cassette (Box 296)
    luncheon - Guest speaker Walter Scharf
  - ASMA, 1990 May 7; audio cassette (Box 296)
    Banquet: Jerry Goldsmith, Century Plaza
  - ASMA, 1989 October 14; audio cassette (Box 296)
    Luncheon, Lalo Schifrin guest speaker, Sportsmen's Lodge, North Hollywood
  - ASMA, 1990 October; audio cassette (Box 296)
    Artie Shaw
  - ASMA, audio cassette (Box 296)
    Luncheon, saxophone quartet.
  - ASMA, 1990 March 16; audio cassette (Box 296)
    luncheon Albert Harris Prescient, speakers Irwin Kostal, Al Sendry.
  - ASMA, 1990 February 15; audio cassette (Box 296)
    Christmas party with an a capella chorus
  - ASMAC, 1992 March 14; VHS (Box 266)
    luncheon & California State University of Long Beach Wind Symphony, Sat., March 14, 1992 Sheraton Universal Hotel
  - ASMAC, 1992 May 19; VHS (Box 266)
    54th Anniversary Celebration May 19, 1992, Century Plaza Hotel, awards to Irwin Kostal and Steve Allen
  - ASMAC, 1992 May 14; audio cassette (Box 296)
    banquet: Erwin Kestel and Steve Allen, Century Plaza
  - ASMAC, 1994 April 20; audio cassette (Box 296)
    Lunch meeting.
  - ASMAC, 1996 October; audio cassette (Box 296)
    Mort Lindsey lunch.
  - ASMAC, 1996 August 27; audio cassette (Box 296)
    Dinner.
  - ASMAC, 1995 April 15; audio cassette (Box 296)
  - ASMAC, 1993 December 14; audio cassette (Box 296)
  - ASMAC, 1991 January 18; audio cassette (Box 296)
    luncheon Speaker Frank De Vol
  - ASMAC, 2001 January 17; audio cassette (Box 296)
    Tom and Nate Scot
  - ASMAC, 1991 September 21; audio cassette (Box 296)
    luncheon Morrie Amsterdam guest speaker
  - ASMAC, 1997 April 16; audio cassette (Box 296)
    lunch - music workshop Les Brown Band
  - ASMAC, 1994 September; audio cassette (Box 296)
    Bernstein luncheon.
  - ASMAC, 1996 June 19; audio cassette (Box 296)
    Lunch at the Ventura Club.
  - ASMAC, 1994 March; audio cassette (Box 296)
    Lunch for new president, Ian Fraser.
  - ASMAC, audio cassette (Box 296)
    lunch Bruce Broughton
  - ASMAC, 1997 February 19; audio cassette (Box 296)
    Lunch meeting, new music.
  - ASMAC, 1996 June 19; audio cassette (Box 296)
  - ASMAC, 1995 November 15; audio cassette (Box 296)
    Luncheon at the Holiday Inn.
  - ASMAC, 1995 September 12; audio cassette (Box 296)
    tribute to Billy May and Van Alexander
  - ASMAC, 1989 (Box 296)
  - ASMAC, 1989; audio cassette (Box 296)
  - ASMAC, 1991 February 16; audio cassette (Box 296)
    luncheon meeting,guest Tommy Tedesco, Sportsmen's Lodge
  - ASMAC, 1992 January 16; audio cassette (Box 296)
    membership luncheon
  - ASMAC, audio cassette (Box 296)
    On item, "luncheon Lennie."
  - ASMAC, 1991 June 15; audio cassette (Box 296)
    Luncheon
  - ASMAC, 1991 April; audio cassette (Box 296)
    Joe Harnell
  - Authors League of America, 1953 May (Box 247)
    Agreement with Screen Writers Guild
  - BMI, 1968-1972 (Box 267)
  - Boy Scouts of America (Box 285)
    Troop 31 committee sample documents
  - California Copyright Conference, 1963 (Box 253)
    Record Business Information - Address to Calif Copyright Conference by Thomas E. Noonan, Research Director, Billboard
  - CISAC, 1973 September 27-29 (Box 260)
    - Warsaw meeting of the International Council of Music Authors and Composers
  - Composers & Lyricists Guild of America, 1965-1966 (Box 247)
    documents, correspondence, letters, minutes
  - Composers and Lyricists Guild of America, 1965-1966 (Box 247)
    CLGA bulletin, v. 1, issue 1, August 1965, v.2, issue 1, February 1966
  - Composers and Lyricists Guild of America, 1955-1956 (Box 247)
    minimum basic agreement first draft submitted to Producers' Association
  - Composers and Lyricists Guild of America, 1956-1962 (Box 247)
    documents, correspondence, minutes, includes reports
  - Composers and Lyricists Guild of America, 1960-1961 (Box 247)
    officers and board members
  - Composers and Lyricists Guild of America, 1953-1960 (Box 247)
    reports, letters
  - Composers and Lyricists Guild of America, 1966 (Box 247)
    Directory of members
  - Composers and Lyricists Guild of America, 1954-1958 (Box 247)
  - Composers' Guild of America, 1954-1955 (Box 247)
    Agreements & Statistics Committee documents, correspondence, minutes
  - Composers' Guild of America, 1954 (Box 247)
    ASCAP documents, correspondence, letters, minutes, includes definitions and plan of written distribution submitted by ASCAP committee of writers and publishers
  - Composers' Guild of America, 1955 (Box 247)
    constitution and by-laws
  - Film Music (Box 298)
    promotional brochure
  - Film Music Museum, 1998-2004 (Box 243)
    Seven-year plan building purchase plan & development of programs
  - Film Music Society, 2001 (Box 243)
    minutes: first meeting 2001, and others
  - Film Music Society (Box 243)
    brochures
  - Film Music Society, 2001 (Box 243)
    Agreement, Preamble, Constitution and by-laws 2001
  - Film Music Society (Box 243)
    Correspondence between Elmer Bernstein, Herschel Gilbert, Henry and Ginny Mancini and others
  - Film Music Society (Box 243)
    legal documents
  - Film Music Society (Box 243)
    committee membership list
  - Film Music Society, 2002 (Box 243)